多美呀
风景如画
- Lovely.
- That is for sure.
那么说这里就是乡下喽？
So this is the country?
瞧瞧后座这没见过世面的小孩
Listen to the underprivileged
child back there, will you?
是的，宝贝，第17滨海大道
嗯，我明白了
- There it is, darling. 17 Shore Road.
- Yeah, I got it.
还好吗，达维？
很好
- Are you all right, Davey?
- I'm fine.
噢，老天！
Oh my God!
那里是我们的家吗？
Is that our house?
不是，达维，不是的
No Davey, that's not our house.
不可能是我们的房子
It can't be our house.
真是浪费
What a waste.
片名：《庭院深深》
=====百度悬疑片吧字幕组=====
领衔主翻：汉大将军袁绍
协力提携：Impression 亡灵的守护骑士 核心期刊大王
穷生韵  vittiger双鱼
译术总监：水浒三国金刚
看吧，早就说“适宜一大家人居住”
Well, it said "suitable
for a large family".
真的好大！
It's so big!
玛丽安
Marian.
你不觉得有点蹊跷吗？
这种房子怎么能那么轻易租到...
Will you be sensible, maybe? Now you don't
rent a house like this for a reasonable...
我想肯定是另有门房或客房留给我们住...
I mean there must be a gate house
or guest room or something...
不，就是它了
No, this is it.
好吧，那就让我们自己动手搞清楚吧
Well there's only one way we
can find out, isn't there.
“冲进死亡之谷，六百骠骑向前”
"Onward into the valley of death,
rode the six hundred..."
但愿屋里有人
I hope they're in.
喔，我们是洛夫一家，是来租避暑房子的
Oh, we're the Rolf's.
We've come about the summer place.
知道，知道，等你们好些日子了！
I know, I know，I've been expecting y'all!
我叫沃克，干杂活的，屋里拾掇得跟新的一样样
My name's Walker, and I'm the handyman.
I keep everything spick and span.
请进来吧，进来吧太太，进来，快进来吧，小帅哥
Y'all come on in. Come on in, ma'am.
Come on in! Come on in, boy!
感觉怎么样？
喔，真的...
- How d'ya like it?
- Oh, it's...
我说，这就是待租的那个房子吗？
Look, is this the place
they're talking about renting?
当然了
It sure is!
又可爱，又漂亮，对吧？那么我们去客厅
It's pretty, ain't it? Beautiful, ain't it?
Ya'll come on
快来看看客厅，太太
in the sitting room. Come on
in the sittin room, ma'am.
随便逛逛，不要拘束
Just turn around on here, and
make yourself at home right here.
请随意，我去叫内布过来
Just make yourselves right at home,
while I go and get the Neb's.
小子，看好家具，知道吗？
Boy, you watch that furniture, ya hear?
难以置信
我也是
- I don't believe it.
- Me neither.
我能出去浪一会吗？
Can I go outside for a
while and mess around?
你就不用来了，你懂的
You don't have to come, you know.
我也不想来，你记得不要乱跑，知道了吧？
No I don't want to come, but
you stay around here, right?
嗯
OK.
- 嘿，听到我说什么了吗？
- 当然听到了
- Hey, you hear what I say?
- Yeah, I heard you.
侬拉组撒？
What are you doing?
真是浪费啊！心疼死我了
Such a waste!It kills me.
不要咸吃豆腐淡操心了
我忍不住
- You musn't take things so personally.
- I can't help it.
- 达维呢？
- 在外头玩
- Where's Davey?
- He's outside.
介意我关门避避味吗？
Do you mind if I shut the
door to keep the stench out?
不介意
No.
玛丽安，你瞧这个
Marian, look at this.
- 真是如梦似幻
- 好美
- This is extraordinary.
- How beautiful.
对，但都是同一副画！
Yeah, but they're all the same!
这副大概是，100年前的？
This one must be what, 100 years old?
这个可能是近些年的
This one's quite recent.
嗯，但是为啥呢？
Yeah, but why?
他们来了
Here they are!
很抱歉让你们久等了
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting.
真是无事不起早
It's been quite a morning.
你百忙之中能把镜子搬了吗？都开裂了
If your busy schedule permits, would you
mind taking the mirror out? It's cracked.
- 又不止镜子开裂
- 老傻逼
- Ain't the only thing cracked around here.
- Old fool.
死老娘们
Grouchy old bastard.
我叫萝丝・阿拉戴斯，我哥哥一会自己过来
I'm Roz Allardyce. My brother will be down
just as soon as he pulls himself together.
吾等是洛夫一家，我叫本
We're the Rolf's.My name is Ben.
这是内人玛丽安
My wife, Marian.
您好
How do you do.
还有个小帅哥，跑哪去了？
There's a boy too, isn't there?
嗯，那是犬子达维，在外面花园里玩呢
Yes, our son, David.
He's out in the garden.
- 没关系吧？
- 没事儿，小孩子就适合在花园里玩
- Is that all right?
- Oh yes. Children are good for the place.
唔，我想可以谈谈细节了吧？
Well, I suppose we'd better
get down to details?
啊，实干的男人，就像我哥一样
Ah, a practical man. Just like brother.
广告上说“价格合理”
The ad did say "reasonable".
我记得是“非常合理”，对有缘人来说再合适不过了
"Very reasonable", as I recall.
And so it is, for the right people.
唔，假设我们是“有缘人”，您的“合理”大概是指？
Well, assuming we are the "right people",
what would your idea of "reasonable" be?
等下，我要先问你们几个问题
Well, I'd like to ask you a few questions first.
就你们三个人租吗？
Would you be taking the house by yourselves?
唔，不，还有本的姑妈，伊丽莎白
Well, no. There's Ben's aunt, Elizabeth.
- 多大了？
- 74了
- How old?
- She's 74.
意思是一个老姑娘？身边有个老姑娘你不嫌弃？
An old gal then? You wouldn't mind having an old gal around?
噢，当然不，伊丽莎白可优雅了
Oh no.Elizabeth is a doll.
你打算从七一建党节租到五一劳动节
And you'll take the place from
the 1st of July until Labour Day
这段时间你会打扫好房子吗？
and you'll keep the place and you'll tend it?
就我们自己？我是说，自己打扫？
By ourselves? I mean, alone?
唔，当然
Well, yes.
我不确定，这屋子太大了
I don't know,
with a house this size
只有我妻子一个人，我不知道能不能...
and only my wife, I don't
know that we'd be...
房子自己会照顾自己，洛夫先生
The house takes care of itself,Mr. Rolf.
相信我
Believe me.
我不想就此展开话题但是...
I hate to make an issue of this but...
...你会如我和哥哥一般爱这座房子吗？
...will you love the house
as brother and I do?
噢，会的，我想会的
Oh yes. I think we will.
那么这一块地收你们900块钱
Then we're talking in the
neighbourhood of 900 dollars.
我不知道要那么...
Look, I don't know that I'm
going be able to make that...
整个夏天都归你
For the whole Summer.
救命！救命！
Help! Help!
啊，我哥哥来了
Ah, that's brother.
- 沃克，沃克，看在上帝的份上！
- 哦，亲爱的
- Walker, Walker, for Christ's sake!
- Oh dear.
- 稳住稳住，我过来了！
- 该死的电梯又坏了
- Hold your horses, I'm coming!
- The damn stairlift is broken again.
- 它在动，在动！
- 失陪一下
- It's moving! It's moving!
- Excuse me.
我要下去！
I want down!
难以置信，对吧？
Unbelievable, isn't it?
得来全不费功夫，没问题宝贝，就这样定了吧
It's an absolute steal! There's no
question, is there darling. We'll grab it.
- 听着，宝贝，我真的不...
- 但是亲爱的，不要白不要
- Look, sweetheart, I don't really...
- But darling, we'd be crazy not to!
如果要了就和他们在一起了，你看看他们，简直...
Well if we were we'd be in step with them,
wouldn't we. Look at them all, they're...
这男的就是个活傻逼，让他滚蛋！
The man's an absolute
idiot, and we've got to
明白吗？明白吗？
get rid of him! Do you understand?
Do you?
这是我哥哥阿诺德，如你们所见，精力旺盛
This is my brother, Arnold.
As you can see, he's full of beans today.
你们就是要租房子的是吧？
So you are the people who want to
rent this house, is that right?
对，我们刚和令妹谈了价钱
Yes, we were just discussing terms
with your, um, lady.
噢，我喜欢他们，萝丝，我喜欢他们
Oh, I like them Roz, I like them.
- 还有个小男孩
- 是的，是犬子达维
- There's a boy, too.
- Yes, our son, David.
- 他在花园里玩耍呢
- 真的吗？带我瞧瞧
- He's playing in the garden.
- Really? Show me.
快点，萝丝，我想瞧瞧
Hurry, Roz, I want to see.
啊哈，看到了！真是可爱啊
Ah, there he is!Isn't he darling.
噢，上帝，多可爱的小男孩，多大了，八九岁？
Oh God, what a charming little boy.
How old is he, eight or nine?
- 都十二了
- 十二了，多萌啊
- No, 12.
- 12? Isn't he sweet.
也是个顽皮鬼，不是吗？
He's full of the Devil too, isn't he?
噢很抱歉，也许他不该到处乱跑...
Oh I'm sorry, maybe he
shouldn't be walking around...
没事没事，让他玩吧，没关系！
No no, leave him alone, he's fine.
He's just fine!
- 你经常租房子吗？
- 看情况了
- Do you rent often?
- It depends.
哦，我妹妹想表达的是
Oh, what my sister's
trying to say is that we
我们对休息与闲暇极度渴望
have this desperate need
of rest and relaxation.
我都成这样了，你也能看出来...
I'm coming apart, as you can see...
- 噢，哥哥...
- 哦吼，哥哥没事
- Oh, brother...
- Oh, brother is right.
你喜欢吗？
Well, do you like it?
- 我们喜欢
- 真的吗？
- We love it.
- Really?
上帝，告诉他们，哥哥，告诉他们这房子有多么生机勃勃
God, when it comes alive.Tell them, brother.
告诉他们夏天的时候的情况
Tell them what it's like in the Summer.
唔，他们不会信的
Well, they'd never believe it.
It's beyond
这超出了你们人生的认知范围
anything that you've
ever seen in your life.
洛夫太太，这房子有几个世纪了
There's centuries in this room, Mrs. Rolf.
- 到处是岁月的痕迹
- 嗯
- There are years, years in this house.
- Oh yes.
当然房子依然还会存在很久
And this house will be
here long, long after
即便到你死了还在，相信吗
you have departed,do you believe me.
实际上它是不朽的
It's practically immortal.
- 我非常诚挚地相信
- 我也是
- I sincerely believe that.
- So do I.
噢，我想对你们来说可能太搞笑了
Oh, I know that must seem funny to you.
但当人们像我和哥哥一样爱这栋房子的时候...
But when people love a house the way
my brother and I love this one...
噢，抱歉，我不是故意冒犯，我只是...
Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't mean to be rude,
it's just that...
...我在等签协议
...well, I was waiting for the catch.
签协议？
Catch?
嗯，你要价900块...
Well, you mean it's 900 dollars and...
...这房子就是我们的了？
...and then it's all ours?
噢，当然还有一件事
Oh, of course there is one other thing.
- 但不能算入协议之内了
- 当然不是
- But it's hardly a catch.
- No, it's not a catch.
我要说的是我的妈妈
It's our mother.
她又怎样？
What about her?
一个看着像60的85岁老太太
An 85 year old woman who could pass for 60.
眼下她想说的是...
Yes now, what she's trying to say is...
我们的妈妈从没有离开过这个房子
that our mother never,
ever leaves the house.
实际上她自己房间都没出过，不是吗？
Well she never leaves her
room actually, isn't that so?
噢，她不会带来麻烦的
Oh, she'll be no trouble at all.
你们都不可能看见她的身影，她一直在睡觉
No, you'll probably never even see her.
She sleeps most of the time.
每当她不睡觉的时候
And when she's not
sleeping, she's listening
她就听自己的音乐，研究收藏品
to her music or working
on her collection.
对，她的图画，照片，收集了几千张
Yes, her pictures, or old photos. You
see, she has literally thousands of them.
都是一生的记忆
Memories of a lifetime.
她是我们最亲爱的人
She is our darling.
你们要做的只是准备一个托盘，每天三次
And all you'd have to do is
prepare a tray, three times a
把它放在她客厅的桌子上即可
day, and just leave it on the table.
In her sitting room.
这个...
Look...
如果我们回家商榷一下再定，您介意吗...
Do you mind very much if we go home,
maybe think about it and let you know...
- 本，别这样！
- 非常感谢
- Ben, no!
- Thank you very much.
- 妈妈
- 达维？
- Mom.
- Davey?
达维，怎么回事？
Davey, what happened?
- 我弄破了膝盖
- 看起来好脏
- I just cut my knee.
- That looks nasty!
- 怎么回事？
- 我从上面摔下来了
- What happened there?
- I fell off a thing out there.
你最好冲洗一下他的伤口
You better wash off his poor little cuts.
我们去厨房去
Let's go out to the kitchen.
- 来吧，我有一些绷带和药品
- 走吧亲爱的
- Come on, I have some band-aids.
- Come on, darling.
你拿着植物到哪去？
Where are you going with that plant?
胡西说它已经死了！
Josie said it was dead!
是吗？
Did she?
看仔细了
Well look again.
哈！还没死透
Huh! Ain't that somethin'.
我想你太过粗鲁了
I thought you were impossibly rude.
是吗？
Was I?
噢得了宝贝，里面都大的能捉蝴蝶了
Oh come on, sweetheart. Someone should
go in there with a large butterfly net.
他们得意忘形了，就这些
They got carried away,
that's all.
不是，不是
Not yet, they didn't.
你不可能900块就租得到
You do not rent an estate
like that for 900 dollars.
为什么？
Why not?
他们醉翁之意不在钱
Maybe they're not
interested in money. Maybe
可能只是想找人料理房子
they want someone who'll
take care of the place.
租吧
Just be there.
好吧，但是你不会想和一个90岁的老女人...
Well all right, maybe. But you don't need
a 90 year old woman just to...
85岁
85.
85和185岁有区别吗？
85 or 185, what's the difference.
你不会把一个老人留给两个陌生人的
You don't leave an old lady like that
with two complete strangers.
你不用担心她，我来照顾她
You wouldn't have to worry about her.
She'd be my responsibility.
- 哦，对，那她要快死了呢？
- 噢上帝
- Oh yeah, sure. And what if she's to die?
- Oh my God.
这房子对你真那么有意义吗？
Does it really mean that much to you?
你自己知道
You know it does.
我会坚强的
I'll survive.
问题是...我也会坚强的
The question is... will
I be able to survive.
我是阿拉戴斯
Allardyce.
你好，洛夫先生
Yes, Mr. Rolf.
干的漂亮，我哥哥会很开森的
Marvellous.
Brother will be so pleased!
七一建党节
July 1st.
我们会准备好一切的，谢谢，再见
We'll have everything ready.
Thank you. Bye.
- 回来这里感觉好吗？
- 不！这一切让我很麻木
- Are you comfortable back there?
- No! Just about everything in me is numb!
除了你的嘴，姑妈
Except of course your mouth, auntie.
噢，小本，我忘了说了，我更新了驾照许可证
Oh Benji, I forgot to tell you.
I renewed my learner's permit.
我下了决心了
I am determined this time.
好吧，我必须承认我很欣赏您的坚持，姑妈
Well, I must admit I admire
your persistence, auntie.
当然我的坚持正是我依然貌美如花的原因
Well my persistence is the reason
I have flourished this long.
你要做的就是，姑妈，开车时学会放松
All you've got to do, auntie,
is learn to relax at the wheel.
我一直都很放松，倒是考官太紧张了！
I always relax at the wheel.
I get nervous inspectors!
我们有很多房间
We'll have lots of room.
我不会落下它的
I can't get over it.
很美，是不是
Beautiful, isn't it.
看起来荒废了
Looks deserted.
不可能吧
Can't be.
怎么了，什么事？
What's the matter, something wrong?
他们已经走了
They had to leave.
走了？
Leave?
“安心的住下来，什么也不用操心。阿诺德和萝丝・阿拉戴斯”
"Enjoy the house and don't worry about
anything. Arnold and Roz Allardyce. "
- 我勒了个去
- 勒的对，这太扯了
- Jesus Christ.
- I know, it's crazy.
万一出了什么事，我们怎么联系他们呢？
What if something goes wrong,
where do we reach them?
老人家向来做一些疯狂的事情
They do crazy things sometimes, old people.
是的，但是这两个是疯狂界的翘楚了
Yes they do, don't they.
But these two are two steps beyond crazy.
- 那老太太怎么办？
- 我会照顾她
- And what about the old lady?
- I'll look in on her.
你说的，这是你的责任，达维！提包过来
You do that. It's your department.
David! Bags.
- 玛丽安，我不敢相信了！
- 都是我们的
- Marian, I can't believe it!
- And it's all ours.
稍等一下
Be right there.
阿拉戴斯女士？
Mrs. Allardyce?
我是玛丽安・洛夫，我们是新来的租客
It's Marian Rolf.
We're the new tenants.
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
你需要点什么吗？
Is there anything you need?
一辈子的记忆都在这儿了
Memories of a lifetime.
玛丽安，你在哪？
Marian, where are you?
- 你上去干嘛？
- 我端走她的盘子
- What have you been doing up there?
- I've been getting her tray.
- 你看到她了？长啥样子？
- 她在睡觉
- Have you seen her? What's she like?
- She's asleep.
我们晚点上来看她
We'll see her later.
听着，包括你
Now, listen. Both of you.
楼上除了我谁也别上去，知道了吗？
These stairs are out of bounds
to anyone but me, all right?
阿拉戴斯女士已经非常老了，照顾她是我的责任
Mrs. Allardyce is a very old lady
and she's my responsibility.
我不想任何人打搅她
I don't want anyone bothering her.
遵命
Crushing.
- 大家伙过来看看我发现了什么！
- 瞎吵吵什么玩意儿？
- Hey you guys! Come see what I found!
- What are you talking about?
来，我带你们去！在厨房里！
Come on, I'll show you!
It's in the kitchen!
我们去看看
Let's go look.
这些钟没一个可以工作，真可惜，它们都相当可爱
None of the clocks are working.
It's a pity, they're all so lovely.
也许需要上发条，等下我来弄好
Probably need winding.
Just wait til I get to work.
你迫不及待想穿上你的护膝和护裆，是不是
You can't wait to get into your
knee pads and jock straps, can you.
- 小本！
- 噢，姑妈
- Benji!
- Oh auntie.
很棒吧？
Isn't it great?
- 绝赞
- 伊丽莎白姑妈，看这个！
- Great.
- Aunt Elizabeth, look at this!
瓦屋，啥都有！
My God, it's got everything!
小本，给你交代个任务，这儿需要新灯泡
Benji, here's your first job!
Needs a new bulb.
好的
Right.
他们是不是很疯狂啊宝贝?
他们真怪，嗯？
So they're crazy are they, darling?
So they're weird, huh?
是的，这是种我可以与之共舞的疯狂
Yeah well, this is the kind
of crazy I can live with.
- 该死..
- 小本!在孩子面前...
- God damn it..
- Benji! In front of the child...
我去给阿拉戴斯夫人送午餐，好吗？
I'll go see about Mrs.
Allardyce's lunch, OK? You
你们尽情吃三明治...
guys just fix a nice
spread of sandwiches...
- 好极了，把它给我！
- 我总是说他慷他人之慨
- Marvellous, give it to me!
- I always said he had it down.
你们看见这些古董了吗？
Did you see those antiques?
我想我看见一些叮当了！
Hey, I think I see some Ding Dongs!
伊丽莎白姑妈，你以前见过这么多贵重古董吗？
Aunt Elizabeth, did you ever see
so many priceless antiques?
真的是叮当！
Hey, they are Ding Dongs!
整整一箱！
A whole case of them!
敬这房子一杯，怎么样？
How about a little
toast to the house, eh?
- 嘿，奴隶！
- 嗨！
- Hey, slave!
- Hi!
太奇妙了，你做了啥？
This is fantastic,
what have you been doing?
你从哪里找到这些地毯的？
Where did you get this from?
就是和卷着靠墙的是同一张
That is the same one that was rolled up
against the wall.
你喜欢吗？这可贵重了
You like it?
It's worth a fortune.
- 我来拿
- 谢谢宝贝
- I'll get that.
- Thanks, sweetheart.
我们离开后你独自做了这么多？
You did all this by yourself since we left?
楼上还有更多呢，你们去镇上怎么样？
And there's more upstairs, I'll
have you know. How was town?
棒极了...
Oh, it was great, great...
乌有之都，如果你懂我说的
Capital of nowhere, if
you know what I mean.
- 把这些袋子放厨房里
- 遵命“把这些袋子放厨房里”
- Put those sacks in the kitchen.
- Yeah, "put the bags in the kitchen"
你怎么不来看我们的游泳池？应该是非常开心的事情
Hey why don't you come and watch us fix the
pool, that should be some kind of a laugh.
忙着呢！
Busy, busy, busy!
你还没搞好吗？
Aren't you finished with that thing yet?
听着，既然你辣么聪明，为什么不自己上来修？
Listen, if you're so God damn smart why
don't you come up here and fix it yourself?
达维,示范给你老爸怎么弄
Davey, go show your father
how to do it.
好吧，我来！
All right then, I will!
你别私下破坏我作为父亲伟岸的形象好吗，老熟女？
Will you quit trying to undermine
my parental authority, old lady?
总好过在下面铲污垢
Rather that than go down there and
shoving it up of that old sewer.
所以我想让它可以工作起来
Yeah, which is kind of why I'm
trying to get this model work.
- 老爸
- 嗯
- Father.
- Yeah.
过来，加油！
Come here. Come on, come here!
机器上有个小玩意叫隔断器
See, there's a little object on
this machines called a cut off.
在这里，试试看
There it is.
Go on, try it.
- 你觉得它还可以工作？
- 我打赌一定可以
- Do you think it will work?
- I'll bet on it.
- 赌什么？
- 5美金
- How much will you bet?
- 5 dollars.
小本,你就是个机械天才！
Benji, you're a mechanical genius!
快看，是墓地！
Hey look, it's a graveyard!
老爸！嘿，看看我发现了什么！一部旧单车！
Hey dad! Hey, come look what I found!
It's an old bike!
你知道吗，达维?这些都是阿拉戴斯家的
You know something, Davey?
They're all Allardyce's.
我找不到一个比1890年更晚的墓碑了
And I haven't been able to find
one any newer than the 1890's.
有点阴森是吗？
Bit spooky, eh?
你想吃糖吗，小家伙？
Would you like some candy, little boy?
别缠着我！
Leave me alone!
你跑不掉的，小男孩！哈哈！
You can't run away from
me, little boy! Ha ha ha!
阿拉戴斯夫人？
Mrs. Allardyce?
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
我很担心你
I am very worried about you.
我们已经过来一周了，而你什么都也没吃
We've been here over a week,
and you've barely eaten anything.
是不是你不喜欢我做的菜呢？
Is it that you don't like
what I've been bringing
是萝丝夫人叫我给您送饭的
you? It's what Roz
wanted me to give you.
您晚上自己下来厨房吃了？您一直这么做吗？
Do you go down to the kitchen at night?
Is that's what you've been doing?
阿拉戴斯夫人，至少您也得说句话
Mrs. Allardyce,
if you would at least speak to me.
妈妈呢？她不是说跟我们一起来吗？
Where's mom? She said she was
gonna come with us, didn't she?
额，你知道你妈妈不会来的
Yeah well, you know your mother don't you.
还在坚持抽烟？
How's your wind hanging on?
比不了从前了
Not what it used to be.
- 你抽太多烟了，知道吗？
- 我知道
- You smoke too much, you know that?
- I know.
并且我还酗酒
And I drink too much.
我是一个淫荡的老女人，肯定活不到80了
And I am a lecherous old lady
and I'll never make 80.
你在游泳池里加了消毒剂了吗？我是说，你知道它可以除菌的
Did you put the chlorine in the pool?
I mean, you know that does kill the germs.
嗯嗯，我对细菌不太感兴趣
Yeah well, I'm not too
interested in the germs.
小屁孩你看，我在跟着一条奸诈的海蛇
You see, it's the sea
serpent I'm after, boy.
那么我们啥时候可以游泳啊？
Well, when can we go swimming?
为啥不先去问问你老母
Why don't you go and ask your mother first.
去吧，快去快去快去！
我在走呢
- Go on, double double double!
- I'm going.
妈妈！
Hey mom!
嘿妈妈，你在上面吗？
Hey mom, are you up there?
我们该去游泳了，妈妈
It's time to go swimming with us, mom.
我哪也找不到她，我翻遍整个屋子了！
I couldn't find her anywhere.
I searched the whole house!
别急，她可能在厕所
Don't worry,
she's probably on the john.
很腻害吧？
Isn't that great?
这个跳水动作我给满分，爸爸！
That was a great dive, dad!
- 噢小本，你应该去参加奥运会
- 就是，就是。。
- Oh Benji, you should be in the Olympics.
- Right, right...
嘿，那是啥？
Hey, what is that?
啥也没有啊，啥也没有
Nothing boy, nothing.
别急我马上过来！
Yeah well, I'm coming out!
小伙子，你也许是个优秀的球手
All right Benny, you
might be a great ball
但是你划得像块石头，明白吗？
player, but you float
like a rock, got that?
知道啦，我会把握好的
Yeah well, I'm coming out anyhow.
达维！那是深水区！
Davey!
That is deep water!
别再卖弄了
Now stop showing off.
爸爸，我是海蛇！
Dad, it's a sea serpent!
不，不，救命！
No no, help!
- 想玩玩吗达维？
- 好哇
- Wanna play then Davey, eh?
- Yeah.
- 玩啥，傻老爸？
- 看好了
- What is it, witless?
- OK.
你就抓住我的肩膀，好吗？
You clutch on my shoulders, OK?
本，不要！
Ben, no!
真好玩！
That was fun!
- 你喜欢这样？想再来一次吗？
- 好
- You like that? Wanna do it again?
- OK.
好了，你们俩，玩够了
All right now, you two.
It's quite enough.
小本，你比被宠坏的孩子还要糟糕
Benji, you're worse
than a spoiled child.
- 确实有点难度
- 你喜欢吗，达维？
- That was really hard.
- You like that, Davey?
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
小本，停下！
Benji, stop it!
本，天啊！你在伤害他！
Ben, my God!
You're hurting him!
本，现在是凌晨两点
Ben, it's after 2:00.
是嘛？
Is it?
你睡着了吗？
Did you sleep?
- 嗯，睡了会
- 回去继续睡吧？
- Yeah, some.
- Want to come back and try again?
额，也许过一会儿吧
Well, in a while maybe.
- 你不能在这抽烟，好吗？
- 为啥！这房子不允许？
- You don't have to smoke in here, do you?
- Why, is it wrong for the room?
本，你不是故意伤害达维的
Ben. You didn't mean to hurt Davey.
- 只是玩得有点过头了
- 玩过头了。。。
- The roughhouse just got out of hand.
- Roughhouse...
你当时不在，玛丽安，佛祖啊
You weren't there Marian, for Christ sake.
是，我不在
No, I wasn't.
对不起，你知道吗
I'm sorry, you see...
我脑子里净想这事，没办法忘记
It's all I can think of.
I can't get it out of my head.
本，我懂你
Ben, I know you.
- 所以我知道你不是故意的
- 我特么肯定不是故意的，玛丽安！
- So I know you didn't mean to do that.
- The hell I didn't, Marian!
我有那个念头想伤害他，你懂吗？有那念头
I wanted to hurt him, do you
understand that? I wanted to hurt him.
你在自责，达维没事了，他很好！
You're punishing yourself.
Davey is all right. He's all right!
如果这事比你想的严重得多呢？
What if it's more serious
than you think it is?
你啥意思？
What do you mean?
我做过的关于我妈妈的梦。。你懂得。。
Those dreams I had about
my mother's... you know...
他们又回来了，玛丽安
...they're coming back, Marian.
亲爱的，那是多久前了啊
Darling, that was such
a very long time ago.
你没做错什么，完全没错
There's nothing wrong with you.
Absolutely nothing.
天啊！
My God!
这全变了，又变成崭新的了
It's completely changed.
It's all new again.
这都是你的，喜欢吗？
It's all yours.
You like it?
嗯，绝赞
Yeah, it's great.
我拿走了电视，它不适合这里
I took away the television, it
was wrong for the room anyway.
你应该原谅情绪
You should
forgive the expression.
我们现在要做的就是找点事给我做
All we've got to do now
is just find something for me to do.
哦亲爱的，有好多事可以做呢
Oh darling, there's loads for you to do.
现在是合适的时间开始攻读你的博士学位
Now's a good a time as any
to start on your doctorate.
- 本，没事的，是吧
- 什么，那个房间？
- Benji. It's all right, isn't it?
- What, the room?
不，昨天，过了很久了
No, yesterday.
It's a long time ago.
我们忘掉它从头再来吧，嗯？
Let's just forget it
and start over again, OK?
噢，多好啊，达维决定开始作画
Oh, how nice.
David has decided to take up painting.
我们要去找一处景色
We're off to search out a view.
嗨，达维
Hi, Davey.
- 你还好吧？
- 挺好的
- How is everything?
- Okay.
- 你带你的画了吗，Davey？
- 带了
- Did you take your paints, Davey?
- Yeah.
- 我们还是朋友吧？
- 哦爸爸！
- We're still friends?
- Oh dad!
- 我再也不想去那游泳池了
- 不，你不必去，达维
- I never want to go back to that pool.
- No, you won't have to Davey.
我保证你不会去
I promise you won't have to.
没有你抱着我我睡不着
I don't like going to bed without you.
我在这下面呆了一段时间了
It's been a while since I was down here.
- 不是吗？
- 是的，我知道
- Hasn't it?
- Yes, I know.
至少过滤机看上去有用，不是吗？
Well, at least the filter seems
to be working, doesn't it?
对，归因于一个天才
Yes, attribute to a genius.
剩下的，都是。。
The rest of it, it's all...
看上去都是。。
It seems to be all...
柠檬油的味道？
Smell of lemon oil?
我拔杂草，我抛光镀铬，我擦洗水泥地
I plucked the weeds, I polished the chrome.
I scrubbed the concrete.
那是啥，宝贝？
What is it, honey?
你知道我不得不下来这。。
Do you know I had to come down here to...
来看你是否胜任
...well, to see if I could.
我觉得我们会把这一切都忘掉
I thought we were going to
forget about all that.
我们试过了，不是吗？
We tried, didn't we.
你似乎有点神经不正常
You seem to have landed
yourself with a bit of a kook.
额，那就是我俩的区别
Well, that makes two of us.
看起来不可思议，你为啥不跳进去？
Looks marvellous,
why don't you jump in?
- 你会跟我一起吗？
- 噢，我没穿我的大衣
- Will you come with me?
- Oh, I don't have my suit.
那你为什么不把你的衣服脱了？
Well then, why don't you
take your clothes off?
如果我先走呢？
What if I go first?
下来吧，这很棒
Come on in.
It's great.
- 这算在治疗吗？
- 是的，算
- Will it aid in the therapy?
- It'll aid the therapy.
噢，为何不呢
Oh, why not.
来吧
Everything.
过来
Come here.
很久没有访客了
It's been a long time between visits.
我怀念他们
I miss them.
现在不适合干那事吧，亲爱的
None of that stuff now, honey.
一点水上运动
A little water sport.
对新陈代谢很有好处，亲爱的
It's very good for the
circulation, you know.
我的代谢很正常
My circulation's fine.
回来！
Come back!
- 玛丽安
- 我跟不上你的生活节奏
- Marian?
- Not on your life.
听着，我没说过这在13年后会爆炸
Look, I'm not saying it's going to be
dynamite after 13 years.
但是肯定的是一些兴奋的表象。。
But surely some semblance of excitement...
我不明白什么突然使我变得令人憎恶
I can't work out what's made me
so repulsive all of a sudden.
令人憎恶？
Repulsive?
你很性感
You're incredibly sexy.
本，我并不想这样！
Ben, I don't want to!
别在这，别在这，不要
Not here. Not here, you can't.
玛丽安，佛祖啊
Marian, for God's sake.
拜托，你不明白
Please. You don't understand.
你一定没明白，求你了！
You mustn't. Please!
早上好！
Morning!
- 你在哪找到它的？
- 大厅壁橱里
- Where did you get that?
- Hall closet.
这所房子充满宝藏
This house is full of treasures.
你整晚没上床，对吗？
You didn't come to bed at
all last night, did you?
在游泳池那的事之后
After the pool...
我去了阿拉戴斯女士的房间看看她是否需要什么
I went up to Mrs. Allardyce's room
to see if she needed anything.
我不知道怎么的
And I don't know how it
happened, I just fell
就在一把椅子里睡着了，我猜可能太累了
asleep in a wing chair. I
guess I was pretty tired.
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
噢，我要去。。修理发动机什么的
Oh, I'm going to... trim
the drive or something.
你咋了？都快吃午饭了
Well what happened to you?
It's nearly lunchtime.
我去！就不能允许别人睡个懒觉吗？
Goodness! Can't anyone ever
oversleep in this family?
我只是觉得这并不像你，姑妈
I just mean it's not like
you, aunt Elizabeth.
你比我们都有活力
You've got more energy
than any of us.
曾经有，我恐怕这个暑假把我榨干了
Had. I'm afraid this Summer
vacation is wearing me out.
太多阳光，你为何不在树荫下面作画？
Too much sun.
Why don't you try painting in the shade?
天啊！我需要去美容院
My God!I need a beauty parlour.
别傻了
Don't be silly.
我不是唯一一个可以用美容院的人
I'm not the only one who could use
the beauty parlour.
你的头发白了不少，玛丽安
You're getting quite a bit
of grey in your hair, Marian.
我知道
I know.
我估计我要变成第二个玛丽阿姨了
I think I take after my aunt Mary.
你知道吗，她33岁就头发全白了
You know, she went entirely grey
by the time she was 33.
噢！达维一直在找你，他想去野炊
Oh! Davey's been looking for you.
He wants to go hiking.
笑神马？
What's funny?
噢，好吧，你知道我现在想干嘛吗？
Oh, me. Do you know what
I want to do right now?
不知道
No?
我只想回去睡觉
I want to go right back up to bed.
- 那难道不糟糕吗？
- 当然不会
- Isn't that awful?
- Certainly not.
为啥你不上那去打个盹？那样对你好些
Why don't you go up there and take a nap?
It'll be good for you.
也许我会的
Maybe I will.
玛德，我不会！
Damn it, I won't!
哦我的耶稣佛祖啊，伊丽莎白，你咋回事啊？
Oh for Heaven's sake, Elizabeth,
what is wrong with you?
阿拉戴斯夫人？
Mrs. Allardyce?
我能进来吗？
May I come in?
玛丽安，我不知道你在这
Marian, I didn't know you were in there.
你咋不睡了？
What happened to your nap?
我想是时候介绍我自己给我们的恩人了
Well I thought it about time I
introduced myself to our benefactor.
她在睡觉
She's asleep.
噢，糟糕
Oh, that's too bad.
我觉得她会喜欢我的画的
I thought she might enjoy seeing
my picture.
当然会的，等她醒过来之后
I'm sure she would dear, when she's awake.
伊丽莎白,我现在进退维谷
Elizabeth, I'm right in
the middle of something.
噢对不起亲爱的，我无意打断你们
Oh I'm sorry dear, I didn't
mean to interrupt anything.
- 你告诉她我来拜访过
- 我知道她会高兴的
- You tell her I came to visit.
- I know she'll appreciate it.
- 如果她想有人陪的话。。
- 我会让她知道的，好吗？
- And if she ever wants any company...
- I'll let her know. OK?
小心台阶
Well, be careful on the steps.
现在回去工作吧，我会没事的
Now you just go back to your work.
I'll be all right.
达维！
Davey!
- 咋的了？咋回事？
- 煤气中毒
- What is it, what's wrong?
- Gas.
- 老天爷啊！他还好吗？
- 还好，还有呼吸
- Oh my God! Well is he all right!?
- Yes, he's breathing.
吸气，儿子
Breathe in, boy.
来，扶着他，我去去就回
Here, hold him. I'll be right back.
快呼吸空气
Breathe the air now.
- 你还好吗，达维？
- 我觉得他好些了
- Are you all right, Davey?
- I think he's better.
发生什么了，小本？
What has happened, Benji?
那个该死的煤气暖炉。。
That damn gas heater...
我不明白，这是怎么搞的？怎么会这样？
I just don't understand how it happened.
How could it have happened?
吃过早饭了吗姑妈？
Have you had any breakfast, dear?
不，我又睡过头了，羞耻啊。。
No, I overslept again.
A disgrace.
- 达维怎么样了？
- 噢，一切都好
- How is Davey?
- Oh, everything's fine.
本从镇里打电话过来，达维没事了，佛祖保佑
Ben called from town.
Davey's all right, thank God.
我难以想象他会有多害怕
I can't imagine how frightened I was.
可怜的小达维
Poor little Davey.
我想对你说的是我没碰过那个暖炉
I want you to know
I didn't touch that heater.
- 你当然没有，姑妈
- 如果我做了，我会记得的
- Well of course you didn't, dear.
- If I did, I'd remember.
- 没人说是你啊
- 我只是给他盖了被子，就这样
- Nobody said you did.
- I just covered him, that's all.
你给它盖了被子？你是说你昨晚在他房里？
You covered him? You mean you
were in David's room last night?
是的，我去看了看他，有时我睡不着
Yes, I looked in on him.
Sometimes I don't sleep.
你到底在他房里干啥了？伊丽莎白
Exactly what did you do
in his room, Elizabeth?
我说了，我给他盖了被子，昨晚很冷
I told you, I just covered him.
It was cold.
这个房子变得非常冷
This house is getting so cold.
你知道的，达维的门总是开着的
You know, David's door
is always open.
但是昨晚门锁了
Last night it was locked.
嗯，我可没锁
Well, I didn't lock it.
我除了毯子其他什么都没碰过
The only thing I touched
was the blanket.
那是我唯一记得的事
Well, that's all I remember doing.
好吧，你没有锁上门，是门自己把自己锁起来的！
All right, you didn't lock it.
It locked itself!
那窗户呢？
Now what about the windows?
窗户是开着的
They were open.
本进去之后窗户可是关着的，你搞搞清楚，伊丽莎白！
They were closed when Ben walked into
that room. Now make sense, Elizabeth!
我怎么搞？
How can I?
你不停的吼我，骂我，我怎么搞得清楚？
How can I... when you keep
shouting at me and accusing me?
我没有骂你
I'm not accusing you.
本去哪儿了？
Where's Ben?
小本会相信我的
Benji will believe me.
我也相信你
I believe you too.
不，你才没有，很明显没有
No, you don't.It's obvious.
我们都会忘事儿，伊丽莎白
We all forget things, Elizabeth...
再说……以你这个年龄……
and... at your age...
我没忘！我知道我干了什么！
I don't forget things!
I know what I do!
当然，亲爱的姑妈
Well, of course you do, dear.
那么，我给你做早餐吧，好么？
Now, why don't you just let me get you
some breakfast?
那个老女人叫什么太太来着……
But what about the old woman Mrs...
噢，我脑子太乱了，她叫……
Oh, I am so mixed up. Mrs. ...
阿拉戴斯太太
Allardyce.
- 是的，阿拉戴斯，也许是她……
- 伊丽莎白姑妈！
- Yes, Allardyce. Maybe she...
- Aunt Elizabeth!
咱们还是姑且忘了这回事儿吧！
Let's just forget this!
告诉本我上楼了
Tell Ben I'm upstairs.
我会把早餐带到你房间里
I'll bring your breakfast to your room.
就像你去她房间那样？
Like you do to her room?
另一个老女人？
The other old woman?
不不，玛丽安，别纠结了
No, no. Don't bother, Marian.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
- 小本
- 我把你吵醒了？
- Benji.
- Did I wake you?
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
想去阳台上喝几杯马提尼吗？
Do you feel up to a few little Martinis
on the terrace?
你知道她跟我说了啥吗？
Do you know what she said to me?
伊丽莎白，她很沮丧，我保证她不是故意要说出那番话的
Elizabeth, she was upset. I'm sure
she didn't mean what she was saying.
她不能这么跟我说话
She has no right
to talk to me like that.
我宁可死……
I would die...
如果我做了什么伤害大卫的事，我宁可去死
I would die
before I did anything to hurt Davey.
你看，你们俩之前都没讲过话
怎么回事，忽然之间就这样了？
Look, you two never had words before.
Why, all of a sudden?
问问你老婆吧
Well, ask your wife.
- 也许我是个老女人
- 伊丽莎白，你不老
- Maybe I am an old woman.
- Elizabeth, you are not old.
但这可不意味着我已经痴呆了
But that doesn't mean that I've
lost all my marbles.
如果我真的像她说的那样关上窗锁上门……
If I had closed those windows or
locked that door, the way she said...
我敢保证她没那么说
I'm sure she didn't say that.
我可是明确的记得……
I'd certainly remember...
你不会忘记像这样的事
You don't forget things like that.
我可不会忘记这么重要的事，是吧？
I couldn't forget something as
important as that, could I?
噢，我很抱歉，小本，只是她让我太难受了
Oh I'm sorry, Benji.
But she's gotten me so upset.
我不喜欢这儿，我想离开这房子
I don't like it here.
I want to leave this house.
你也是这么想的，我知道你是
You feel the same way,
I know you do.
听着，伊丽莎白，我们都很难受
Look Elizabeth, we're all upset.
为什么你不下楼来喝几杯呢？
Now why don't you come downstairs
and have those drinks?
权当是给玛丽安道歉的一个小机会
Even if it's just a little chance
for Marian to say she's sorry.
好吧
All right.
但我这么做全是因为你，小本
But only for you, Benji.
我爱你
I love you.
你知道吗？
当然
Do you know that?
I do.
本，你吓到我了
Ben, you scared me.
你知道你伤她有多重吗？
Have you any idea just how
much you've hurt her?
对不起，但她昨晚在达维房里
I'm sorry, but she was
in his room last night.
玛丽安，她干嘛要撒谎呢？
Why should she lie, Marian?
我可没说她在撒谎，她只是不记得了
I didn't say that she lied.
She simply does not remember.
那么我是否可以认为她应该对所有这一切都负责？
And I suppose she's responsible for all
the other things that go on in this house?
唔，我可不明白这是什么意思
Well, I don't know what
that's supposed to mean.
好，要是你不介意，我想下楼了
Now if you don't mind, I'd like
to go downstairs.
难道我不应该先见见她？
Well, shouldn't I meet her first?
- 我的意思是，她在哪儿呢？
- 她就在房间里睡觉！
- I mean, where is she?
- She's in her bedroom, asleep!
本，她并不喜欢有人在这儿
Ben, she doesn't like anyone up here.
她……没错
Her... collection.
亲爱的，为什么你不干脆让我把这儿锁起来？
Why don't you just let me lock up, dear?
你干嘛这么紧张？
Why are you so nervous?
我没有紧张，我只是不想让她太过难受
I am not nervous.
I just wouldn't want to upset her.
你干嘛总是锁着她的门？
Why do you keep her door locked?
她就是喜欢这样，她是个老女人了
She likes it that way.
She's an old woman.
- 她……
- 给了你钥匙？
- She...
- Gave you the key?
不是，钥匙在信封里
No, the key was in the envelope
the Allardyce's left.
能开门锁的钥匙也在同一个信封里吗？
And were the keys belonging to all
those clocks in the same envelope?
那些钥匙在锁盒里，你问这个是什么意思？
The keys to the clocks were in
the clock cases. Why do you ask?
我只是好奇你是否把所有的时钟都拧了发条
I just wonder whether you wound
all those clocks by yourself.
就这样
That's all.
我当然拧了
Well, of course I did.
亲爱的，你这算啥，刑讯逼供吗？
What is this darling, a third degree?
这都是些什么？
What's all this?
让本花时间做的小事情？
好让他高兴点然后从你眼前消失？
Time to throw Ben a little something?
Keep him happy and out of your way?
你就是这么想的吗？
Is that what you think?
玛丽安，老实说，我不知道该怎么想
To be perfectly frank Marian,
I don't know what to think.
也许你可以告诉我
Maybe you can tell me.
好吧，我试试
All right, I'll try.
我很抱歉，那晚在泳池我不该那么做
I'm sorry about the way I acted
at the pool the other night.
我都不知道自己干嘛要那么做
I don't know why I acted that way.
也许你要花点时间才知道
Perhaps you need a little more time
to work that one out.
大卫，小心……
Davey, be care...
看看你做的事！
Look what you did!
- 你什么也别碰！
- 我不是故意的！
- Don't you ever touch a thing!
- I didn't mean to do it!
你别想再碰什么好看的东西！
Don't you ever touch
a beautiful thing!
- 本，我……
- 玛丽安，你到底出什么事了？
- Ben, I...
- Marian, what is happening to you?
没事
Absolutely nothing.
那他妈到底是为什么你要那样对达维！
Then what the hell was that performance
with Davey back in there!
这个房子……
This house just...
……比我想象的还要复杂
...is more than I thought it would be.
玛丽安，亲爱的，这房子不属于你
Marian, this house is
not yours, sweetheart.
我们并不拥有它，你懂吗？
We do not own it, do
you understand that?
但看着房子是我的责任，只要我们还住在里面，不是吗？
But it's my responsibility for
as long as we're here, isn't it?
请有点耐心，我需要多一点时间
Please be patient with me.
I need more time.
多点时间干嘛？
让更多人牵扯进来？
More time for what?
To get more involved with all this?
玛丽安，这个夏天快结束了
Marian, the Summer is almost over.
- 我能问你个问题吗？
- 当然可以
- Do you mind if I ask you a question?
- Of course not.
哪个对你而言更重要？这房子，所有这些……
What's more important to you?
The house, all this...
……还是我们？
...or us?
这算是什么问题？
What kind of a question is that?
好吧，那我换种方式
All right, I'll put it another way.
如果我求你……
If I was to ask you...
你会放弃这一切吗？
would you give it up?
放弃？
Give it up?
为什么？
Why?
要是我没能及时抓住达维呢？
What if I hadn't reached Davey in time?
那跟这房子又有什么关系？为什么要离开？
What does that got to do with this house?
Or with leaving?
本……我真不敢相信你竟然是认真的！
Ben...
I can't believe you're serious!
噢，我认真的，玛丽安
Oh, I'm serious, Marian.
你知道你讲的东西听起来有多荒谬吗？
Do you know how ridiculous you're sounding?
难道你真的是想跟我说这个房子才是罪魁祸首？
Are you actually trying to tell me
that this house is responsible?
你能为了我放下这一切吗？
Would you give it up for me?
我是说，哪怕你认为这些都是我的臆想？
I mean, even if you thought it
was in my head, in my mind?
你能吗？
Would you?
爸爸！
妈妈！
Dad!
Mom!
爸爸，是伊丽莎白姑婆！
Dad, it's Elizabeth!
她在这儿
She's up here.
噢，老天啊
Oh my God.
玛丽安，带着达维离开这儿
快带他离开，快！
Marian, get Davey out of here, please.
Get him out now, please!
达维的专职医生电话是多少来着？
What's the number of that doctor
I used when Davey was ill?
- 在哪儿呢？
- 放在客厅桌上
- Where is it?
- On the hall table.
看着她
Stay with her.
打通了吗？
Did you get him?
没有
No.
忙音
It was busy.
总不可能忙一晚上吧
Well it can't be busy all night.
对吧？
Can't they?
他们都很忙，玛丽安
彻底乱成了一锅粥
They were all busy, Marian.
Every God damn one I tried.
就连接线员都无暇他顾
Including the operator.
很意外吗？
Surprised?
我不知道你什么意思
I don't know what you're talking about.
我要下楼自己试试
I'll go down and try him myself.
好吧，你去吧
Yes, you do that.
- 打通了
- 你打通了？
- I got it.
- You got him?
玛丽安，所有的线路都是忙碌状态，我说的是真的
But all the lines were busy, Marian.
I didn't imagine that.
不，我很确定没有忙音
No, I'm sure you didn't.
重要的是医生会赶来
The important thing is he'll be here.
就没有什么事是我能做的吗？
Isn't there something I can do?
不，你去瞧瞧达维，好吗？
No, no.
You go and check on Davey, OK?
然后在楼下等医生过来
And then wait for the doctor downstairs.
尘归尘，土归土
Ashes to ashes,
and dust to dust.
让往生者安宁
In the sure and certain
hope of the ressurection
让在世者重获解脱……
of eternal life through
Jesus Christ, our Lord...
基于她的勇气和信念，这位良善之人……
And in her courage and faith,
this good woman is now...
现已与吾主在k的天国中……
joined in eternal peace
with her Maker ...
同享安祥……
in His Divine Kingdom...
哀恸之人必得安慰
And we who grieve must take solace
in the fact...
一如吾等必因辛劳而得褒奖
that we, too, are promised life eternal,
as our reward for our good work.
我很喜欢烛光晚餐
I love eating by candlelight.
玛丽安，生活有时就这么让人恶心，不是吗？
Well, life sure as hell
goes on, doesn't it Marian.
确实如此
And why shouldn't it?
- 你不坐下来吗，亲爱的？
- 实不相瞒，我……
- Aren't you sitting down, dear?
- To be perfectly frank, I...
我没什么胃口
I do not have an appetite.
我说，伊丽莎白都已经死了
难道你一点也不在意？
Look, Elizabeth is dead.
Doesn't that mean anything to you?
我相当在意，达维！
It means a great deal to me.
Davey!
玛丽安，我不确定除了这栋破房子
Marian, I'm not sure that
anything means a great deal to
还有什么是你真正在意的，你明白吗？！
you except this bloody house,
do you understand that?!
噢，这可不对
Well, that isn't true.
那你怎么解释自己缺席了伊丽莎白的葬礼？
Then how do you account for your absence
at Elizabeth's funeral?
你知道我不能留下阿拉戴斯太太一人
You know I couldn't leave
Mrs. Allardyce alone.
呵，我觉得咱们都不想讨论这事儿是吧？
Oh, I don't think we
want that on the table,
至少不想在这张餐桌上
do we sweetheart? Not
on the pretty mahogany.
你为什么不把它倒出来，然后把瓶子带回厨房呢
Why don't you pour it, and bring
the bottle back to the kitchen.
- 这儿没有多余的杯子
- 唔，这儿有个高脚酒杯
- But there aren't any glasses.
- Well, there's a goblet.
比玻璃杯强，还是银质的
Is better than glass.
It's silver.
但我不想用高脚酒杯，我就想要个玻璃杯
But I don't want a goblet, I want a glass.
达维，你听见妈妈的话了
你把她的桌子弄乱了
You heard what your mother said, Davey.
You are messing up her table.
- 你现在要坐下了吗？
- 我跟你讲，玛丽安，我不饿
- Are you going to sit down?
- I have told you, Marian, I'm not hungry.
好，多亏了你，现在我也不饿了
Well now, thanks to you, neither am I.
打电话给那老女人
Call the old lady.
我想见她
I want to see her.
本，离那扇门远点！
Ben, stay away from that door!
- 玛丽安，开门
- 我没法开
- Marian, open this door.
- I can't.
唯一的钥匙在她那儿，我没有，这是锁住的
She has the only key.
I don't have that key, it's locked.
好吧，那你还知道什么？
还有什么是你一直都知道的？
All right, what is it you know?
What is it you've known all along?
放开我
Let me go.
拜托
Please.
咱们要离开这房子
We're getting out of this house.
你听到我的话了吗？我说咱们要离开这房子！
Did you hear what I said?
I said we are leaving this house!
我们怎么离开呢?
Well, how can we?
怎么做呢？
How?
咱们就打包走人，就这么简单
We just pack up and go, that's how.
本，你能让我先把这房间锁了吗？
Ben, will you just let
me lock this room up?
玛丽安，你就不能别再说这房间了吗！
Look Marian, will you stop
talking about this room!
这全都是你的一厢情愿，这房间，这屋子，还有那个老女人
It's all you ever think of, the
room, the house, and the old lady.
我是真正在乎她的人
Well, she depends on me.
只有我是
I am the only one.
没人，从来没人像我这样关心她
There is no one, no one, to
take care of her except me.
现在，你不能指望我……
Now, you can't expect me to...
你中毒了
You're obsessed with it.
- 中了剧毒
- 我没中毒！
- All of it.
- I'm not obsessed with it!
玛丽安，这房子要毁掉我们
Marian, this house is destroying us.
亲爱的，这房子是我们梦寐以求的
Darling, this house is everything
we've always wanted.
它是我们的。。。
And it's ours...
只要。。。
For as long as...
玛丽安。。。
Marian...
不管你是不是和我们一起。。。
Whether you come with us or not...
明天。。。
Tomorrow...
。。。我们打道回府
...we're going back.
回去？回哪去？
Going back? To what?
回去我们的老地方
To what we had.
我们无处栖身
We had nothing.
那你觉得我们在这里能得到什么？
And what do you suppose we've got now?
- 达维，醒醒
- 嗯？
- Davey, wake up.
- What?
- 醒醒，我们要走了
- 什么？
- Wake up, we're leaving.
- What?
房子在莫名地。。。
Somehow the house is...
- 。。。莫名的变动
- 什么？
- ...it's changing.
- What?
木板。。。一些木板和瓷砖。。。
The boards... some of the
boards and tiles...
。。。它们在被。。。
...they are being replaced...
。。。新的代替
...by new ones.
你别说话，我们走，OK？
Now, don't ask me why.
Just get out of here, all right?
- 等等，爸
- 快走！
- But dad, wait a minute.
- Get out!
爸!
Dad!
- 停！停！
- 你进去那里！
- Stop it! Stop it!
- You get in there!
我的神！
Oh my God!
停，爸！停下！
Stop it, dad! Stop it!
慢点！等等妈妈！
Slow down! Wait for mom!
停下，求你了，停下！
Stop it, please, stop it!
我不知道。。。
他撞了头好像
I don't know...
He banged his head or something.
他很好，宝贝，我要接你们回去
He's fine, dear.
I'm going to take you back.
你。。。接受这一切。。。
You... are accepting this...
。。。因为你是它的一部分！
...because you're part of it!
你是一部分吗？
Are you a part of this?
爸？爸，你怎么了？爸？
Dad? Dad, what's wrong? Dad?
他会好吗，医生？
Will he be all right, doctor?
他打了镇静剂，会睡一晚上
He's heavily sedated, which means
he'll sleep through the night.
我恐怕到了明早他要去住院治疗
But by tomorrow morning I'm afraid
he's gonna require hospitalisation.
晓得了
I see.
你懂的，我们这里没有合适的设备
Of course, you understand,
we don't have the proper
你要带他去城里
facilities here. You'll have
to take him into the city.
他会没事吧，医生？
But will he be all right, doctor?
我不是这方面的专家
Well, I'm not a specialist
in these matters
洛夫女士，好好照顾他会。。。
Mrs. Rolf, but with the
proper care he'll...
我一定会的
I'm sure I can give it to him.
如果明天要见我，我就在办公室
If you need me tomorrow
I'll be at my office.
- 谢谢你，医生
- 请留步
- Thank you, doctor.
- I'll see myself out.
妈？
Mom?
爸还好吗？
Is dad OK?
很好，甜心，医生刚刚说他需要多休息
Yes, sweetheart. The doctor just said
he needs some more rest.
- 顺利吗？
- 嗯，是的
- Feel all right?
- Yeah, I guess.
我们明天回去吧？
Can we go home tomorrow?
噢，我不这么想，爸爸在这里会更好
Oh, I don't think so sweetheart.
Daddy will be better off here.
- 你怎么现在还不睡？
- 晚安
- Now, why don't you go to sleep?
- Good night.
达维，我做午饭的时候你去外面
Davey, come on out while I fix lunch.
别这样嘛，我又不进去
Oh come on mom, I won't
go in the deep end.
不，你进来很久了，你的衣服呢？
No, you've been in long enough.
Now, where's your robe?
噢，我想是落在我房间里了
Oh, I think I left it in my room.
没关系，去陪你爸爸，我给你带过去
Well, that's all right. Stay with your
father, and I'll bring it with me.
嘿，爸？你还好吗？
Hey, dad?Are you OK?
嘿，想看我游泳吗？
Hey, you wanna see me swim?
看，我现在很好，锻炼了一整天
Look, I'm pretty good now,
I've been practising all day.
你想看我去下面吗？
You wanna see me go in the deep end?
我可以现在可以游到那，你知道吗
I can swim down there now, you know.
好吗？看
Okay? Okay, watch.
我在练习给你看，看！
I've been practising for you.
Watch this!
达维！离那边远点！
Davey!
Stay away from that end!
爸爸？爸爸！
Dad? Dad!
救命！
Help me!
你还好吗。。没事吧，哈尼？
亲爱的？
Are you OK.. are you all right, honey?
OK, darling?
我努力。。。
I tried...
爸爸！他能说话了
Dad! He's talking.
- 我很害怕眼睁睁看着
- 我动不了。。。
- I was afraid I'd have to watch.
- I couldn't...
是的，亲爱的，你当然动不了
Yes, darling. Of course you couldn't.
我讨厌这鬼地方，我要离开这，我恨这儿！
I hate this place.
I wanna get out of here. I hate it!
达维，我们也是
Davey, we are.
我们今天就离开这鬼地方
We are leaving this place.Today.
嘿，我记得你之前就说过我们要离开
Hey, I thought you said we were gonna go.
- 就走，甜心，现在
- OK
- We are, sweetheart. Right now.
- OK.
你还好吗？
确定吗？
Are you OK?
You're sure?
我忘记告诉阿拉戴斯太太我们要走
I forgot to tell Mrs. Allardyce
that we're leaving.
玛丽安。。。求你了
Marian... please.
我不想回去那房子
I don't want you to go
back into that house.
本，别这样
Ben, don't be silly.
我们不能就这样丢下那个老太太
We can't just drive off and leave
that poor old lady sitting
可怜的坐在那，都不知道我们走了
up there without even telling
her we're driving off.
算了吧妈，我们就这样离开，好吗？
Come on mom, let's just
get out of here, OK?
求你了，我不想回去那里
Please, I don't want
you to go back in.
拜托，我只去留个电话号码
Hey come on fellas, I'll
just leave her our number
如果需要她可以联系我们，OK？
so she knows where to reach us in case
she needs us, OK?
就一下下
It will just take a moment.
阿拉戴斯夫人？是我
Mrs Allardyce?It's me.
我是玛丽安
It's Marian.
我们要去找你妈妈
I got to go and get your mother.
玛丽安，你在里面吗？
Marian, are you in there?
阿拉戴斯夫人？
Mrs. Allardyce?
抱歉，我不是故意打扰你，我是来找玛丽安的
I'm sorry, I didn't wish to disturb you,
but I was looking for Marian
她说过要来告诉你我们打算走了
She said she was going to come up here
and tell you that we were leaving.
阿拉戴斯夫人
Mrs. Allardyce.
嘿，我知道她来过这
Look, I do know that she came up here.
你一定和她讲过话，能告诉我她在哪吗？求你
You must have spoken to her.
Would you tell me where she is, please?
阿拉戴斯夫人，我在和你说话，回答我，可以吗
Mrs. Allardyce, I am talking to you.
Will you answer me, please.
回答我
Will you answer me.
快回答我！
Will you answer me!
玛丽安？
Marian?
我一直在等你，本
I've been waiting for you, Ben.
我的神！
Oh God!
妈妈！
Mom!
噢，漂亮！
Oh, it's beautiful!
辉煌。。。就像原来一样
Just glorious...
like it used to be.
我们的妈妈。。。
And our mother...
她回来了
She's back.
我们的宝贝
Our darling.
也回来了。。。
Restored to us...
。。。和从前一样美
...in all her beauty.
一样美！
Her glory!
和我们在一起。。。又一次
With us... once again.
《庭院深深》全片完  谢谢观赏
=====百度悬疑片吧字幕组=====
领衔主翻：汉大将军袁绍
协力提携：Impression 亡灵的守护骑士 核心期刊大王
穷生韵  vittiger双鱼
译术总监：水浒三国金刚